# Carlos Ricco van der Ley

□ crvander@outlook.com

% linkedin.com/in/crvander

(805) 331-3818

Santa Barbara, CA

### **SUMMARY**

Over 20 years of problem-solving and practicing analytical skills (Brazilian Air Force + work experience). Combine patience, determination, and persistence to troubleshoot client issues. Ability to interact and effectively communicate with people from diverse backgrounds, highlighting teamwork and problem solving.

## **EXPERIENCE**

LANDMARKGLOBAL SANTA BARBARA, CA

INTERN IT OPERATOR Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

Performed Security Audit and Penetration Test

FIRST CLICK INC. SANTA BARBARA, CA

INTERN FRONT/BACK-END DEVELOPER

Upgraded and Implemented web sites / E-commerce

SANTA BARBARA CITY COLLEGE SANTA BARBARA, CA

**TECHNOLOGY TUTOR** 

Assisted with the use of computer hardware and software

Performed technical assistance to computer system users

**FOREVER LIVING PRODUCTS - BRAZIL** 

**BRAZIL** 

**ENTREPRENEUR** Jul 2005 - Jul 2012

- Contributed to opening new markets in different states
- Assisted team members to improve their communication, public speaking, and leadership skills
- Solid knowledge, understanding, and application of the principles of assessing customers' needs, meeting quality standards for services, and evaluating customers' satisfaction

### **BRAZILIAN AIR FORCE - BRAZIL**

**BRAZIL** 

MECHANICAL AND FLIGHT ENGINEER

Jan 1993 - Jun 2009

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

Aug 2016 - May 2017

- BETA TESTER / WEB DEVELOPER
- Inspections, adjustments, and repairs to ensure safe and efficient aircraft operations
- Handled functional issues by coordinating with software developers and testers
- Developed and maintained corporate intranet and internet websites

## **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO

SAN DIEGO, CA

BS IN DATA SCIENCE

Jul 2020 – Jun 2023 (Expected)

SANTA BARBARA CITY COLLEGE

SANTA BARBARA, CA

MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE (AS) LIBERAL ARTS AND SCIENCE (AA)

Jan 2016 - May 2020

## **SKILLS**

Machine Learning, SQL, R, Python, Pandas, Dask, AWS, Scikit-Learn, Statistical Analysis, Data Visualization, D3, Flask, Web Development.